你正被监视着 政府有一套秘密的系统
You are being watched. The government has a secret system...
一个无时无刻都在监视你的机器
A machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我知道 是因为这机器是我造的
I know, because I built it.
我设计这机器是用来查找恐怖活动的 但它却什么都能看到...
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror, but it sees everything...
包含普通人的暴力犯罪 像你一样的普通人
Violent crimes involving ordinary people, people like you,
这种犯罪 政府认为不相干
crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为 所以我决定自己插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档  一个有能力进行干预的搭档
But I needed a partner, someone with the skills to intervene.
由于被当局追捕 我们只能秘密行动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远不会找到我们 但无论是受害者还是行凶者
You will never find us. But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码蹦出来 我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第15集
Person of Interest S01E15 720p HDTV x264
又有新号码了 Reese先生 他的名字叫做Michael Cahill
We have a new number, Mr. Reese. His name is Michael Cahill.
你就掌握了这么点儿信息 Finch?
That all you got, Finch?
Cahill今年33岁 单身 没有妻子 没有孩子 没有宠物
Cahill's 33 years old, single, no wife, no children, no pets.
无牵无挂的那种人 跟你有点像 Reese先生
No attachments of any kind. A bit like you, Mr. Reese.
在肯尼迪机场时发现这个人的护照有点问题 移民局的人正赶过来 我们应该等一会
Problem with this guy's passport at Kennedy. I.N.S. is on the way. We're supposed to wait.
"这个人" 刚飞了15个小时过来做心脏移植手术
"This guy" just flew 15 hours for a heart transplant.
我不会让他在离医院16个街区的地方等死的
I'm not letting him code out here 16 blocks from the hospital.
不管从哪方面看
For all intents and purposes,
Cahill表面上都像是一个守法的好公民
Cahill appears to be an upstanding citizen.
表象大多是假的
Appearances can be deceptive.
我们给了你不少钱 所以给我安静点 好吗?
We're paying you good money, so keep your mouth shut, okay?
没错 Cahill是个罪犯
Indeed. Cahill's a criminal.
入室抢劫 用致命武器攻击警察
B&E, assaulting an officer with a deadly weapon.
现在他升级到走私了
Now he's graduated to smuggling.
走私团伙的老大叫Vargas
Crew's run by a guy named Vargas.
这些人什么都走私 谁找他们的麻烦 他们就杀死谁
These guys will move anything. And if someone gets in their way, they'll kill everyone.
你觉得我们应该从何入手 Reese先生?
How do you suggest we proceed, Mr. Reese?
和往常一样 Finch 他们越危险...
As usual, Finch. The more dangerous they are...
你还在等什么? 开车
What are you waiting for? Go.
我越想靠近他们
The closer I want to be to them.
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：墨墨塔 Shally 校对：酒囊饭袋 时间轴：荒川小白脸
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 时间轴：荒川小白脸
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
让我去跟警察谈吧
Let me talk to the cop.
我来吧
I got this.
别动
Stay put.
放松 孩子
Relax, kid.
Cahill能把警察打发走
Cahill will talk us out of this.
如果他不能 他就会杀死他
And if he can't, he'll just kill him.
我从没见过比他更恨警察的人
I never met a guy who hated cops as much as this guy.
是啊 他怎么去了这么长时间?
Yeah, so what's taking him so long, huh?
他要是叫后援的话 我们就死定了
He calls backup and we're all dead.
他没有后援 HR那我都打点好了
He doesn't have backup. I'm all paid up with HR.
你都搞定了?
You found this rig?
尾灯坏了 我们的朋友不过是出于好心 告诉了我们一声
Tail light's out. Our friend was just letting us know as a courtesy.
这是你的一份
Here's your cut.
我还以为今晚要白忙活一场了呢
Thought I was gonna have to waste them.
Mike Mike 别激动 哥们
Mike, Mike. Hold up, brother.
这孩子今晚学到的不少了 Mike
Kid's done enough learning for tonight, Mike.
再犯一次错 我就杀了他
One more mistake, I kill him.
- 有麻烦了 Finch Cahill出去了 - 现在凌晨三点还不到呢
Got a problem, Finch. Cahill's on the move. It's nearly 3:00 in the morning.
- 你知道他要去哪吗? - 不知道
- Any idea where he's going? - No.
但不管他要干什么 肯定不是什么好事
But whatever he's up to, can't be good.
Finch Cahill正在一户人家附近踩点
Finch, Cahill's casing a home.
布鲁克林果园路3404号
3404 Orchard Avenue in Brooklyn.
他闯进去了 Finch
He's breaking in, Finch.
我需要信息 现在
I need some information. Now.
屋主姓Tulley
Homeowner's last name is Tulley.
他是个警察 John 你得拦住Cahill
He's a police officer. John, you've got to stop Cahill.
- 爹地! 爹地! 你回来了 - 嘿 孩子
Daddy! Daddy! You're home. Hey, boy.
上床睡觉的时间到了
Time for all good boys to go to sleep.
睡醒见 晚安
Later, champ. Sleep tight.
Reese先生 看来你不是唯一一个卧底的人
Mr. Reese, it appears that you're not the only person working undercover.
- 他们可能会更新我们的指令 - 你觉得他们会通过CIA吗?
They might be updating our orders. You think this is being run through Langley?
我们甚至不应该在这个国家里执行任务
We're not even supposed to operate in this godforsaken country.
你要把那玩意擦多少遍才肯罢休?
How many times are you gonna clean that thing?
在陆军里 他们教我们挨枪子的最快方法
In the army, they taught us the fastest way to get shot
就是不擦干净你的武器
was to fail to clean your weapon.
在海军陆战队 他们教我们擦干净武器的最快方法
In the marines, they taught us the fastest way to clean your weapon
是用它杀人
was to shoot a couple people with it.
我能找的最好的了
Best I could do.
便宜的波兰伏特加
Cheap Polish vodka.
包裹还安全吗?
Package secure?
万事俱备... 只差去哪里交货的命令了
We have everything we need... Except the orders of where to deliver it.
不是万事俱备吧 你这少个杯子
Almost everything. You're missing a glass.
找到了
Found it.
那个包裹 他会有什么下场?
The package. What'd he do?
- 那就不关我们的事了 - 那人看起来像是政府部门的
- Not our concern. - Guy looks government.
本地人不喜欢我们抓他们的人
The natives don't like us taking their people.
他是政府的人
He's government.
打算把我们的东西卖给中国人
Tried to sell something of ours to the Chinese.
- 什么东西? - 软件
- What? - Software.
还是别的什么 我不知道 也不在乎
Something. I don't know, don't care.
我们的任务就是...
We've got one job in this...
把他送到一个他永远都回不来的荒芜之地
Render him to some black hole from which he will never return.
如果文件有问题或是飞机没燃料了 你就结果了他
If the papers don't clear or the plane runs out of fuel, you execute him.
你上次回国是什么时候 朋友?
When was the last time you were in country, my friend?
今天晚上不会来电话了 出去找点乐子吧
Call's not coming in tonight. Go get yourself some R&R.
别忘了你是在敌后
Don't forget you're behind enemy lines.
你要是在这被抓了 没人会去救你
You get caught here, you're on your own.
Cahill彻底把我给耍了
Cahill certainly had me fooled.
Cahill的真名叫做Daniel Tulley 2003年从警校毕业
Cahill's real name is Daniel Tulley. Graduated from the police academy in 2003.
从那时起 所有的工作记录都消失了
Since then, all work records have disappeared.
纽约警局似乎费了很大的力气来掩盖他的身份
The NYPD seems to have gone to great lengths to hide his identity,
包括给了他一个假的社保号码
including a false social security number.
但如果机器给出了他的号码的话 那意味着有人发现他是警察
But if the machine gave us his number, it may mean that somebody's figured out he's a cop.
- 我们应该给他提个醒 - 他的工作本身就是有生命危险的
We should warn him. Risking his life is what he signed up for.
我们要是出了什么差错...  可能导致的弊会大于利
We play this wrong... We could do more harm than good.
有人过来了 Finch
We've got company, Finch.
你要是想暴露身份的话 还不如直接拿着这个呢?
Why don't you just wear it if you're gonna go announcing yourself?
你职业生涯的最大成功就近在咫尺了 你却决定回来度个小假?
Less than a day away from the biggest collar of your career, you decide to take a holiday?
- 这个人是Cahill的联系人 - 没人跟踪我 我只是...
The man's Cahill's handler. No one followed me. I just...
需要感受一下正常的生活
Needed to feel normal.
我们手里关于Vargas的罪证够多的了 你现在可以归队了
We got enough on Vargas. I could pull you out now.
我们五个月前就能拿下Vargas 他只是个走私犯
We could have gotten Vargas five months ago. He's just a smuggler.
L.O.S.才是我们想抓的那个人
L.O.S., that's the guy we want.
传说他下次会亲自去提货
Word is he's picking up the next shipment in person.
L.O.S.只是个传说 Michael
L.O.S. is a fairy tale, Michael.
这就是上次送货时L.O.S.给我的 纯度是100%的
I took this from the last delivery from L.O.S. It's 100% pure.
我们找到大鱼了 直接的源头
We found the big one. The direct source.
不管这个L.O.S.是谁...
Whoever this L.O.S. is...
如果没人敢动他的货 那肯定是有原因的
If no one's stepping on his shipments, there's a good reason.
我不想最后穿着一身黑 不得不通知你妻子...
I don't want to wind up in a dark suit, having to inform your wife...
我负责我的部分 你负责你的
I'll take care of my end, you take care of yours.
我认为Vargas警局里有眼线
I think Vargas has a cop in his pocket.
昨天晚上他对于那个警察没有后援太自信了
Last night he was too confident that black and white wouldn't have backup.
他警局里有人在保护他 我很确定
He's got someone protecting him from the inside, I'm sure of it.
我会调查看看的
I'll look into it.
Cahill认为Vargas警局里有人
Cahill believes Vargas has a cop on his payroll.
我也这么认为
So do I.
Vargas说HR那都打点好了...
Vargas was talking about being paid up with HR...
跟想让Elias杀死Carter的是同一拨受贿警察
The same corrupt cops who were willing to let Elias kill Carter.
Carter警探!
Detective Carter!
Snow探员
Agent Snow.
我不知道你还在市里呢
Didn't realize you were still in town.
我去了趟北部
I took a trip upstate.
- 我现在肯定那人肯定在和某个警官合作 - 你怎么会这么说呢?
I'm sure now that our boy's working with a police officer. What makes you say that?
在Catskills的一个兽医诊所发现了他的指纹
Found his fingerprints at a veterinary clinic in the Catskills.
然后我确定John从没去过那里
And yet I am certain that John was never there.
我希望他的新朋友能幸运一点
I hope his new friend is luckier.
John习惯利用别人 然后抛弃他们
John has a tendency to use people and then, well, discard them.
我还记得他以前搭档的葬礼 仿佛就在昨天
I remember his old partner's funeral like it was yesterday.
一个漂亮的女人 像你一样
A pretty woman. Like you.
在他利用完她之后 弃之如敝屣
After he was done with her, not so much.
说句话 警探
A word, Detective.
你知道枪击了John的人刚还在这吧?
You do realize the man that shot John was just here?
Snow探员不知道我的存在...
Agent Snow doesn't know about me...
也不知道我与我们共同朋友的关系
Or my arrangement with our mutual friend.
我们需要你的帮助 警探
We need your help, Detective.
这个人叫Michael Cahill 还被称为Daniel Tulley...
This man is Michael Cahill, otherwise known as Daniel Tulley...
在一个走私团伙卧底的缉毒警察
Narcotics Detective working undercover with a smuggling ring.
Reese先生刚刚打入他们的内部
One that Mr. Reese has just infiltrated.
他当然会这么做
Of course he has.
但我们认为纽约警局内有内鬼
But we believe that there's a leak at the NYPD.
不用我说 你就知道Cahill的身份 要是暴露的话 会发生什么
I don't need to tell you what can happen if Cahill's cover is blown.
- 而你希望我找到这个内鬼 - 我只是需要你来解释一下事情是如何运作的
And you expect me to find this leak. I just need you to explain the system.
- 有谁知道Cahill卧底的事情? - 只有他的联络人
Who would know about Cahill's being undercover? Only his handler.
那有权浏览他的报告和档案的人呢?
What about the people that have access to his paperwork, files?
卧底的档案只有纸质材料  所以像你这种人是无法黑进去的
Files on undercovers are kept only as hard copies, so people like you can't hack into them.
你这话太伤人了 警探
Words wound, Detective.
文件存在保险箱里
The files are kept in safes
保险箱放在由内务部看管的屋子里
in one room controlled by IAB.
但是 只有联络人才有卧底资料保险箱的密码
However, only the handlers have the combinations to their UC's safe.
想闯进去的人
Anyone tries to break in,
内务部都会把他们送去监狱 永远别想出来
IAB will send them on a one-way trip to Rikers.
我们得在别人到手前 毁掉Cahill的文件
We would need to destroy Cahill's file before anyone could retrieve it.
我们? 闯入警察总部可是联邦重罪
We? Yeah, see, breaking into 1PP is a federal offense.
我会搞定这点的
I've got it covered.
让我猜猜 你又要找我帮忙了吧
Let me guess, you need another favor.
有人可能要把一个卧底缉毒警察的身份
Someone might be selling out an undercover narc
卖给一个叫Vargas的走私犯
to a smuggler named Vargas.
去找找你缉毒队的狐朋狗友们
Pay some of your dirty buddies in narcotics a visit.
那些人不相信我了
Those guys don't exactly trust me anymore.
我最近干了不少好事 还得到了一次嘉奖
I've been getting some good collars lately too. Even got a commendation.
你的屁股让你得到的那次嘉奖
Your ass got you that commendation.
是时候再当回坏人了
Time to get your hands dirty again.
嗯? 你不用说
Yeah? You don't say.
哪一个?
Which one?
那就找出来 现在
Well, find out then. Now.
出事了 Finch Vargas接到了一通电话 他脸色不太好
Something's wrong, Finch. Vargas got a phone call, and he's not happy about it.
我们现在要去送货
We go ahead with the delivery now.
因为我们要是不去 L.O.S.会杀死我们的
Because L.O.S. will kill us if we don't.
我有几次是请你过来吃晚餐的?
How many time I invite you for dinner?
- 你过来都是为了生意 - 生意才是王道 没时间吃饭
All business with you. Business is good. No time to eat.
你知道 我一直在想
You know, I've been thinking.
你我可能想重新商量一下我们的交易
You and I might want to renegotiate our deal.
你知道 做我们这行的 思考...
You know, in our business, thinking...
是最危险的事情
Is the most dangerous thing you can start doing.
或者我可以直接把货送到L.O.S.手里?
Or maybe I take the shipment directly to L.O.S.?
把你撇掉
Cut you out.
好吧 好吧 我跟你说
Fine, fine. Tell you what.
我多给你点怎么样 行吗?
How about I give you a little something extra, okay?
只给你? 如何?
Just for you? Yeah?
坚持住 坚持住!
Come on, come on!
出去! 我们走! 快走! 把他放在后面
Out! Let's go! Move it! Get him in the back.
都上来了 走吧
That's it. Hit it.
笨蛋们 快点
Fools, hurry up.
- 好了 - 好的
- Yeah. - All right.
坚持住
Come on.
躺在这
Lay down there.
- 我还以为我们要去见L.O.S.呢 头儿 - 我们是要去
Thought we were meeting with L.O.S., boss. We are.
只是先停下来一会
Just making a little pit stop first.
把你们的手机拿出来 然后毁掉
Take your phones out and destroy them.
他们在布鲁克林停下来了
Drop looks to be in Brooklyn.
马上就会有精确的定位了
Should have the exact location in a second.
Signal Connectionm Lost
出什么事了?
What happened?
你们的武器... 都扔进来
Your weapons... Toss 'em in.
所有人都要 现在
All of you. Now.
你们中间有一个是警察
One of you is a cop.
一两个小时之内 我就能知道是谁
In an hour or two, I'm going to find out which one.
活着的人会去完成这次的送货
Whoever's still alive will finish making this delivery.
美国是一个一切皆有可能的地方...
That America is a place where all things are possible...
那些还在怀疑我们祖先的美国梦 是否还存在于我们时代的人
Who still wonders if the dream of our founders is alive in our time.
- 你介意么?  - 不 一点也不
- Do you mind? - No, not at all.
民主的力量
The power of our democracy.
- 像下地狱一样的事儿哈? - 今晚你们就能找到答案
Hell of a thing, huh? Tonight is your answer.
你住在纽约 还是到这出差?
You, uh, live in New York, or you just visiting?
- 出差 - 你从哪来的?
Just visiting. Where you from?
老家吗?
Originally?
华盛顿的Puyallup
Puyallup, Washington.
你说的是真的吗? 我妻子也是Puyallup的
Are you kidding me? My wife's from Puyallup.
- 你还住在那吗? - 我离开那里很久了
You still live there? Not for a long time.
我因为工作的关系 到处出差
I travel for work.
我以前也是那样
Ah. I used to do that.
那太痛苦了 我再也不那样了
It's brutal. Not anymore.
我和我妻子刚给我们的第一套房子
Me and the wife just put a down payment
付了首付... 就在New Rochelle
on our first house... Up in New Rochelle.
不用说 听着就不错
You don't say. Sounds nice.
嘿 你知道吗? 我妻子又迟到了 跟往常一样
Hey, you know what? My wife's running late, as usual.
我得给她打个电话 确保她没事
I better give her a call. Make sure she's okay.
我跟你说什么了 John?
What did I tell you, John?
你让我去喝一杯
You told me to get a drink.
在纽约你可以和八百万人中的任何一个喝酒
And of the 8 million people you could be drinking with
你却碰巧挑了娶了你前女友的那个人?
in New York City, you just happened to pick the one who's married to your ex?
你们得帮帮我 拜托了 拜托了
Gotta help me. Please, please.
他失血太多了 我们得送他去医院
He's losing too much blood. We should take him to the hospital.
在我知道谁是叛徒之前 谁都不许走
No one's going anywhere until I know which one of you is a rat.
喝口水
Sip it.
慢一点 慢一点
Slowly, slowly.
带我去医院吧 Mike 求你了!
Take me to the hospital, Mike, please!
你丫闭嘴 否则老子就亲手结果了你
Shut it or I'll put you out of your misery myself.
- 帮帮我 拜托 - 我们得弄个止血带
Help me, please. We need to build a tourniquet.
干嘛这么麻烦?
Why bother?
如果我们把血止住 没准就能让他闭嘴
If we stop the bleeding, it might get him to shut up.
- 你们接到报警电话了? - 有人点了Su Chin的饭店
You guys get a call? Someone lit up Su Chin's.
缉毒科出岔子了 真倒霉
Narco thing gone South. Damn shame.
- 皇后区最好吃的宫保鸡丁 - 对你的损失深表遗憾
Best Kung Pao in Queens. Sorry for your loss.
你搭档呢?
Where's your partner?
让我猜猜 在皇后区?
Oh, let me guess. Queens?
事实上 我现在找不到他了
I'm having a little trouble finding him, actually.
- 你失去他了? - "失去"这个词用得太严重了
- You lost him? - "Lost" would be a strong word.
但 是的 警探 为了回答你还没说出口的问题
But, yes, Detective, in answer to your unspoken question,
- 我确实需要你的帮助 - 你有什么信息?
I do need your help. What you got?
一个车牌
A license plate.
他流了很多血
He's lost a lot of blood.
- 你觉得他会撑过来吗? - 够呛
- Think he'll make it? - Probably not.
我们尽力了
We did the best we could.
有信息了
All right, we got a break.
我们要去布鲁克林码头找一个仓库
We're looking for a warehouse on the Docks in Brooklyn.
紧急呼叫 各单位准备支援
Dispatch, we need multiple units to respond.
Delete all messages?
No Messages.
瞧你那蔫样 很闹心么
Look what the cat drug in. You look terrible.
瞧瞧你 你要把黄尿给戒了
Look at you. You might want to lay off the brown liquor.
什么风把您给吹来了?
To what do I owe the pleasure?
有个叫Neil Vargas的走私犯 你认识他么?
Smuggler by the name of Neil Vargas. You ever heard of him?
想抓住他来着 看我能否分掉他一杯羹
Want to twist his arm a little bit, see if I can get a percentage of his scores.
你应该会感兴趣
Thought maybe you might want to get in.
你消失了整整三个月
I don't hear a peep from you for three months,
现在又这样突然出现
then all of a sudden you show up with this new score.
我很难信任一个朋友被关进监狱的人
Hard to trust a guy whose buddies wind up in prison.
想找Vargas吗? 那就乖乖申请
You want to shake down this Vargas? You gotta be a good boy and ask permission.
如果HR还有收他黑钱 就能找到
If this guy isn't already paid up with HR, you could have at it.
- 找谁能联系到HR? - 近在眼前
Who do I contact if I want to contact HR? You already have.
- 保持联系哈 - 过期不候
I'll be in touch. I won't hold my breath.
喂
Yeah?
警察总部那要换班 这将是我们唯一的机会
There's gonna be a shift change at 1 Police Plaza. This may be our only opportunity.
什么机会?
Opportunity for what?
- 到了吗 警探? - 喂 小点声
Are you in position, Detective? Whoa, whoa, easy with the volume there.
难怪阳光大叔成天一副窘样
No wonder Mr. Sunshine's always in a foul mood.
- 你会习惯的 可能要花点时间 话说你没多少时间了 - 好吧
You'll get used to it. It takes a little time, - which you're running out of. - Okay, okay.
- 什么方案 老牛仔?  - 这方案很简单
- What's the plan, Kimosabe? - The plan is simple.
监管房间的内务部警探
The IAB Detective that patrols the room
会在换班前做最后一次检查
makes one more inspection before the next shift begins.
所以你有约8分半钟的时间
That will give you approximately 8 1/2 minutes
蒙取钥匙卡 打开保险箱 在Vargas的内线到达前
to spoof the key card, break into the safe, and retrieve Tulley's file
找到Tulley的档案
before Vargas's informant can get to it.
知道了 是挺简单的
Yeah, sure. Sounds simple.
一定要把读卡器对准钥匙卡
Make sure you point the reader at the key card.
- 还有啥要嘱咐的? - 别被逮住
Anything else I should know? Yeah, don't get caught.
谢了 我会尽最大努力
Thanks a lot. I'll try my best.
Fusco 你来这干嘛?
Fusco, what are you doing here?
- 你干嘛呢? - 我要走了
- What are you doing? - Uh, I was just leaving.
我来帮队长办点事
I'm just, uh, running an errand for the Captain.
- 回见  - 好的 祝你今天愉快
- Later. - Yeah, you have a good day.
好的
All right.
- Carter警探 - 找到三个关于那个车牌的记录
Detective Carter. Got three possible hits on that license plate.
是南布鲁克林一辆警车的 自动分析仪上记录的
It was logged by an automatic plate reader on a Cruiser in South Brooklyn.
我这就去查
I'm gonna start looking.
太好了 谢谢 警探
I'm glad to hear it. Thank you, Detective.
- Finch Finch? 在听吗? - 我在呢 说吧
- Finch, Finch? You there? - I'm here. Go ahead.
好了 我要进去了
All right. I'm going in now.
- 不好意思 - 没事
I'm... I'm sorry. That's fine.
小菜一碟 我进来了
Presto. I'm in.
- 好了 现在干嘛? - 关掉荧光灯
Okay, what now? Turn off the fluorescents.
用我给你的手电
Use that light I gave you.
- 看到指纹了吗? - 3-5-8
Do you see the prints? 3-5-8.
开始按吧 密码可能是任意组合
Start punching numbers. The code could be in any sequence.
- 我们快没时间了 警探 - 各种组合都试了 没用
We're running out of time, Detective. I tried every combination. It's not working.
帮个忙啊
A little help, please?
- 有没有哪个指纹比较模糊? - 5号有点模糊 咋了?
Was one of the prints smudged? Yeah, 5 is a little blurry, why?
它被按了两次 试下3-5-5-8
It's used twice. Try 3-5-5-8.
5-5-8-3
5-5-8-3.
8-5-3-5
8-5-3-5.
还真打开了
Can't believe it worked.
- 我拿到Tulley的档案了 - 很好 警探
- I've got Tulley's file. - Good job, Detective.
Tulley现在安全了
Tulley's safe for now.
你还有23秒时间离开
You have 23 seconds left.
Fusco警探 对吧?
Detective Fusco, right?
我们对你和你的伙计们进行了调查
My department investigated you and your buddies.
- 听着 事情不是你想的那样 我可以解释 - 解释为什么销毁机密文件?
Listen, this isn't what it looks like. I can explain. Explain shredding a confidential file?
你被逮捕了
You're under arrest.
我不得不销毁那文件
I had to destroy that file.
- 有位卧底警察有生命危险 - 你怎么知道的?
There was a UC whose life was in danger. And you know this how?
有人跟我说的
I've got a guy... tells me things.
- 什么人? 说啥了? - 小心说话 警探
What guy? What things? Careful what you say, Detective.
我们能看顾你 但这些人在找我们的朋友
We can look after you, but these men are looking for our friend.
这人是谁并不重要
Look, it doesn't make a difference who the guy is.
你只需知道 有位警察命悬一线 我在救他
All you need to know is that a cop's life was on the line and I was trying to save him.
喂 我遇到麻烦了 没法拿到文件了
Yeah. I got a problem. I couldn't get the file.
有个白痴把文件毁了
Some idiot destroyed it.
不管谁是内鬼 你那边有人给他打电话
But whoever the rat is, I got word he just made a phone call from your location.
什么意思 有人打过电话? 不可能
What do you mean, somebody made a call? That's impossible.
我得处理点事
I've got to take care of a situation.
- 晚点再打给你 - 你是那个内线
- I'll call you back later. - You're the informant.
他的手机呢?
Where's his phone?
等我把你毙了就不难找了
Whole let easier for me to search you after I shoot you.
他拿了
He took it.
说什么呢 我啥时拿了
You kidding? Huh? The hell I did.
放开我!
Get off me!
应该不难找到
Shouldn't be too hard to find out.
看来找到我们的内鬼了
Looks like we found our rat.
是你跟警察告发了L.O.S.? 那次送货?
You tell the cops about L.O.S.? Huh? The delivery?
别浪费时间了 我的援兵很快就到了
You shouldn't waste time. My reinforcements will be here any minute.
如果真那样 我的人会告知我的 你也早死了
If that were true, I would have gotten a call from my guy and you'd be dead.
我们这样是行不通的
We're not getting anywhere.
给我点时间 我来让他开口
Give me time alone. I'll get him to talk.
你最好让他开口 否则你俩就等死吧
You better get him to talk or you both catch a bullet.
你到底是谁?
Who the hell are you?
- 我知道你不是警察 - 没错
- I know you're not a cop. - No.
但我以前是卧底
But I've been undercover.
我知道你最大的梦想 是回家和你妻子Melinda团聚
I know the only thing you want in the world is to go home to your wife Melinda,
还有你儿子Danny
to your son Danny.
直说了吧 你不了解我
Let's get one thing straight. You don't know me.
我知道你的联络人叫Byrne
I know your handler's name is Byrne.
我知道你从2003年就开始干这个
I know you've been on the force since 2003.
我知道你还有个叫Connor的弟弟 在你高中毕业一个月后吸毒过量
I know you had a younger brother Connor who O.D.'d a month after you graduated high school.
你怎么...
How did you...
所以你才这么想抓到L.O.S.
That's why you're so committed to catching L.O.S.
你是FBi还是?
What, are you a fed or something?
差不多吧
Something.
我能帮你逃走 帮你回家
I can help you escape. Help you get home.
如果你真那么了解我 就该知道我不会回家的
If you know me so well, then you know I won't go home.
- 只要L.O.S.还没被铲除 - 你的身份快要暴露了
Not while L.O.S. Is still operating. Your cover's gonna be blown.
你留下来 会冒很大风险
You stay, you risk everything.
你的生活 你的家人
Your life... Your family.
你能给我妻子捎个话吗?
Can you get a message to my wife?
告诉她我爱她
Tell her I love her.
我们会想办法让你回家的
We'll find a way to get you home.
你可以自己告诉她
And you can tell her yourself.
- 他们在废品厂交易 - 他来了
The exchange is at the scrapyard. He's coming.
好吧
That's right.
- 他说什么了吗? - 我还需要点时间
He say anything yet? I need more time.
好吧 没时间了
Okay, there's no more time.
- Ajax死了 我们得处理掉尸体 - 不 交给我吧
Ajax is dead. We've gotta dump the bodies. No, no. Let me do it.
我要亲眼看看这内鬼死去时的表情
I want to see the look on his face as I end this rat.
那你来吧
Help yourself.
有什么计划 John? 要杀掉这人吗?
What's the play here, John? We're gonna kill this guy?
把他的尸体放进酸液缸里溶掉?
Dissolve his body in a bathtub full of acid?
还是只是吓吓他?
Or are you just scratching an itch?
他叫Peter
His name is Peter.
37岁 年薪17.5万
He's 37, makes 175,000 a year.
他到底是个好男人 还是杀人恶魔 我也不知道
Is he a good guy or a serial killer? I don't know.
但不管怎样 他比你更能爱护她
But either way, he'll take better care of her than you could.
所以我犹豫是否带你回来
This is why I worried about bringing you back.
你和这里其他人看着是一样
See, you look like the rest of these people...
但你以后就不一样了 不是吗?
But you're not like them anymore, are you?
如果他们知道你的工作...
If they knew what you'd done...
- 他们跟你不是一个世界的 - 我们在黑暗中前行
You're barely even the same species. We're walking in the dark.
我听过这场演讲
I've heard this speech before.
抱歉 我不知道你佳人有约呢
Sorry, I didn't realize you were meeting someone as well.
亲爱的 你没跟他介绍你老婆吗?
Honey, you didn't tell him about your much-better half?
等下可有得受了
There will be hell to pay later.
- 我们该走了  - 等等
- We should get going. - Wait.
再等等 我很想介绍我妻子给你们认识
Two seconds. Um, I really want you to meet my wife.
她肯定很高兴能认识Puyallup来的人
She's going to get a kick out of meeting someone from Puyallup.
我懂的 真的
I get it. Believe me.
我第一次回来时 直接回了家
First time I rotated back, I went straight home to my family.
我在门外的出租车里呆看了3个小时
I sat outside in the rental car for three hours, just watching.
我想我可以告诉他们我所有的见闻
And I realized I could tell them everything that I'd seen,
所有做过的事 但他们根本不会懂
everything that I'd done, and they wouldn't understand a single word.
这不是什么演讲
This isn't some speech.
我们没有...在黑暗中前行
We're not... walking in the dark.
我们就是黑暗
We are the dark.
- 噢 Peter - Jessica
- Oh, Peter. - Jessica.
- 抱歉 我来晚了 - 该撤了 John
I'm sorry. I'm sorry I'm late. It's time to go, John.
- 我想给你介绍这里的一对夫妇 - 好啊
There's a couple at the bar I want you to meet. Okay.
貌似只有我们了?
- Huh. - I guess it's just us?
- 是啊 - 嗯
- Yeah. - Yeah.
干嘛呢你?
What's the holdup?
没了这个他就不好辨认了
He'll be harder to I.D. without this.
整辆车都会被烧毁 不会留下任何痕迹
Car will burn hot enough. Won't be anything left to I.D.
要搭车吗? 我就在隔壁
Need a lift? I was in the neighborhood.
真是我的幸运之日
My lucky day.
你说的幸运之日
Your version of a lucky day
就是中枪后 被扔进火海?
is being shot and lit on fire?
没击中 擦了下皮而已
Not shot, just grazed.
我很幸运 Cahill枪法很准
Lucky for me, Cahill's an excellent marksman.
找你的
It's for you.
- Cahill去哪了? - 那啥 我...
Where's Cahill? Oh, I'm...
好吧 Finch 就当你问候了
Fine, Finch. Thanks for asking.
Cahill去跟L.O.S.交易了 没有支援
Cahill went to the exchange with L.O.S. Without backup.
- 在哪? - 南布鲁克林废品厂
- Where? - South Brooklyn scrapyard.
已经到了
Headed there now.
- 除了你腰上那把 还有别的枪吗? - 有
You got any firearms besides that piece? Yeah.
姑娘你很懂我心嘛
Girl after my own heart.
- Reese先生 - 干嘛
- Mr. Reese. - Yeah.
我们有新麻烦了
We have one other problem.
Fusco警探在Vargas的内线手上
Vargas's informant has Detective Fusco.
他处境肯定也很危险
And his life is most certainly in danger.
Reese先生 我们没时间两个都救了
Mr. Reese, I'm not sure we have time to save them both.
好的 谢谢
All right, thanks.
这位就是L.O.S.?
This is L.O.S.?
你可真能折腾
You made a mess out of this.
下次别让我等这么久
Next time, don't keep me waiting.
退后! 退后!
Back! Back!
你们都退后 不然我崩了你们老大的脑袋
You stay back, or I spill your boss's brains on the asphalt.
知道你是在恐吓谁吗?
Do you know who you're threatening?
你的救兵呢 小子?
Where's your backup, son?
放他走
Let him go.
那你得开枪才行
You're going to have to shoot.
换我就不会这样做
I wouldn't do that.
趴好 谁都不准动
Stay down. Don't nobody move.
- 跪下 - 你要逮捕我吗?
On the ground. You gonna arrest me?
我14小时后就会被释放
I'll be out in 14 hours.
然后就会去找你
Then I'm coming for you.
恐吓警察 我指控时会给你加上这条
Threatening a police officer. I'll add that to the charges.
不会有指控的 至少跟那个沾不上边
There won't be any charges. At least none that stick.
- 他是中情局的 - 什么?
He's CIA. What?
- 中情局的人也贩毒? - 政府不能彻底铲除毒品犯罪
The CIA's trafficking drugs? The government couldn't win the war on drugs...
就利用它来给反恐战争提供资金
So they're using it to fund the war on terror.
- 有那么众所周知么? - 可能吧
This is common knowledge? Doubtful.
中情局就是靠秘密建起来的
The company's built on secrets.
我把我的命都押在这上面
I risked my life for this.
- 我要逮捕他 - 你要这样做了他们会毁了你的职业生涯的
- I'm taking him in. - You do and the company will ruin your career.
这还是往好了说
And that's if you're lucky.
- 我还是要逮捕他 - 你也老是喜欢博运气
I'm taking him in. Always liked to push my luck too.
知道我为啥干得这么好吗 Fusco?
Do you know why I'm so good at my job, Fusco?
- 我能看得出坏警察 - 你应该照照镜子
I can tell a dirty cop when I see one. You should try looking in the mirror.
你可能觉得自己变好了
You know, you may think you've gone clean,
找到了上帝 佛 或者非洲萨满
found God, Buddha, or some African shaman,
但到了最后 你的双手仍然肮脏 永远都是
but at the end of the day, your hands are still dirty. Always will be.
听见了吗?
You hear that?
- 我什么都没听见 - 这就对了
I don't hear nothing. That's right.
没有警笛声 没有扩音器
No sirens, no bullhorns.
没人来救你 没人关心你
No one's coming to save you. No one cares.
那个...跟你告密的人...
That guy... The one who tells you things...
他利用了你 然后就把你扔下不管
He used you, then let you rot like a piece of garbage.
如果你告诉我是谁
Might as well tell me who it is.
起码你还有机会找他算账
At least you'll have the satisfaction of repaying the favor.
你以为你是第一个拿枪指我的人吗?
You think you're the first person to put a gun to my head?
不 但我将是最后一个
No. But I will be the last.
是啊 可能吧
Yeah, maybe you will.
你中过枪吗?
You ever been shot?
脑中想着各种疯狂的事
Craziest things go through your mind...
好在我是换了干净内衣 那些龌龊的就不说了
Glad I put on clean underwear, hid that stash of porn.
遗憾你儿子将来会发现他老子是个坏警察
Sorry that your son had to find out that his old man was a dirty cop.
然后你会意识到自己活不长了
Then you realize you're gonna die.
就想努力去做点好事
You try to go down doing something good.
- 这事你也说不准 对吧 - 跪下
You wouldn't know about that, would you, - you dirty sack? - Kneel.
- 你这时间掐得也太紧了吧? - 起码我没来晚
Cutting it kind of close, don't you think? At least I'm not late.
我得上报这事 我能把这宗枪击摆平
I gotta call this in. I can make this a good shooting.
这电话是他跟Vargas联系的唯一证据吗?
That phone is the only proof that this guy was working with Vargas?
- 是的 - 给我看看
- Yeah. - Let me see it.
- 你这是干嘛? - 你不能坦白 Lionel
- What the hell are you doing? - I can't have you coming clean, Lionel.
你要打入HR 接近他们
I need you inside HR. Get close to them.
警察总部里有摄像头
There are cameras inside of 1PP.
他们会知道我是跟这家伙一起离开的 这可是一级谋杀 你知道吗?
People will know that I've left with this guy. We're talking murder one. Don't you get it?
就因为这点
That's the point.
你需要有HR的朋友帮你掩护
You'll need your friends at HR to help you cover this up.
我才刚找到点做好人的感觉
I was just starting to enjoy being a good guy for a change.
你已经做过好事了 Lionel
You've done some nice work, Lionel.
抱歉 但你在内部更有价值
I'm sorry, but you're more useful inside.
我的双手一旦肮脏 就永远肮脏 对吧?
My hands are dirty, always will be, huh?
- 我们要带妈妈去医院吗? - 是的 孩子
- Are we taking mommy to the hospital? - Yeah, champ.
你要有小弟弟喽
You're about to have a new little brother.
我肯定忘东西了 我早就该收拾了
I'm sure I forgot something. I should have packed a week ago.
亲爱的 怎么了 你还好吗?
Honey, what is it? You okay?
我爱你 很爱你
I love you... So much.
我知道
I know.
Snow警探已经安排释放L.O.S.了
I thought you might like to know that Agent Snow has arranged the release of L.O.S.
一个小时内他就能出来
He'll be out in less than an hour.
- 你打算怎么办? - 我会看着Cahill 确保他安然无恙
- What do you plan to do? - I'll keep an eye on Cahill and make sure he stays safe and sound.
他就快有宝宝了 到时肯定有的是动静
He's about to have a screaming infant. I doubt he'll be anywhere close to sound.
真可怜
Poor guy.
都这么久了 Mark 他们竟然会派你来帮我
It's been a long time, Mark. Surprised they sent you down here for me.
你了解中情局 他们只为自己想
You know the agency. They always take care of their own.
整个交易被搞砸了 估计我们亏了两三千万
The whole deal went pear-shaped. Probably cost us 20 million, 30 million.
先给我搞定那两个逮捕我的警察
First thing to take care of are those two cops who brought me in...
某个卧底 还有个女警探
Some undercover and a female detective.
我给过他们警告了 他们必须滚蛋
I gave them both fair warning. They gotta go.
- 我们得发个信息 - 你总是这么冲动 Ray
We gotta send a message. You're always impulsive, Ray.
你不能杀警察
You can't go around killing cops.
你也不该让自己被捕 我警告过你
And you really shouldn't have gotten yourself arrested. I warned you.
你在这儿可是身处敌后 上车吧
You're behind enemy lines here. Come on.
收到你信息了
Got your call.
看来你遇到点麻烦
Looks like you got yourself in a little trouble.
- 遇到突发事件 - 突发事件一般用不着铁铲
It was an accident. Most accidents don't require a shovel.
帮我摆平这事 我会很感激的
Help me make this go away. I'll be indebted.
你不止会感激我 老兄
You'll be a little bit more than indebted, my friend.
你现在是HR的人了
You belong to HR now.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第15集
Person of Interest S01E15 720p HDTV x264
-= 破烂熊字幕 =-
Stay tuned for scenes from our next episode.